A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants O-R FA732F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Grants - O to R, 1941-2010
  - Pacific Oaks (08750448), 1987 April 01-1988 May 31 (Reel R5632)
    Support for planning & initial activities of pacific oaks-pasadena unified school district's early education partnership
    Miller, Shelby H.
  - Pacific Oaks (08900045), 1988 September 01-1991 November 30 (Reel R6187)
    Support for the pacific oaks - pasadena unified school district's early childhood education partnership.
    $302,000.00; $302,000.00
    Miller, Shelby H.; Molnar, Janice M.
    United States; Pasadena (Calif.)
  - Pacific Rivers Council, Inc. (09300156), 1992 October 01-1997 January 31 (Reel R7204)
    Support for its initiative to restore rural communities and watersheds in the pacific northwest
    Pacific States; Watersheds--Northwest, Pacific; Forests and forestry -- Northwest, Pacific
  - Pacific Union College Association (05600378), 1956 June 29-1966 June 28 (Reel R0301)
    $154,500.00; $154,500.00
  - Pacific University (05200157), 1952 (Reel R0053)
    Financing publication of the 1952 hillman lectures of dr. Norris e. Dodd on world food supplies
    $1,000.00; $1,000.00
  - Pacific University (05600792), 1956 June 29-1966 June 28 (Reel R0326)
    $149,500.00; $149,500.00
  - Pacific University (09850662), 1998 March 01-2002 November 30 (Reel R8996)
    For U.S. internships in arts administration, stage design and stage management for Vietnam Drama Theatre staff
    $126,500.00; $126,500.00
    Salemink, Oscar J. H. M.; Bailey, Charles R.
    Vietnam; Theater--Vietnam; Cultural relations
  - Pacific University (10350195), 2002 November 01-2003 April 30 (Reel R9028)
    For the participation of the Vietnam-America Theater Exchange's American partners in a planning retreat
    DiGregorio, Michael R.
    United States; Vietnam
  - Pacifica Foundation (09851928), 1998 October 01-2001 November 01 (Reel R8856)
    Partial support to fund a marketing consultancy, promotional campaign, and program development activities for democracy now!
    Human Rights; Media Arts and Culture
    Cox, Larry; Funabiki, Jon; Santos, John Phillip
    United States; Mass media--United States--Citizen participation
  - Padang Institute Of Teacher Training And Education (07950621), 1979 May 07-1979 June 06 (Reel R1284, Reel R4983)
    Assistance to the ikip padang library in adding to their english language collection
    $633.00; $633.00
    Ashabranner, Brent K.
  - Padatik (08350999), 1982 December 01-1983 November 30 (Reel R4072, Reel R4257, Reel R5941)
    Support for participation of foreign theatre experts in an inter- national seminar on indian dance traditions and modern theatre
    $15,000.00; $14,652.38
  - Padatik (08850202), 1987 November 20-1988 November 19 (Reel R6107)
    Support for symposium on the relevance of traditional martial arts to modern performance (india)
    Vellani, Anmo l.
  - Padjadjaran University (07350869), 1973 August 21-1974 August 20 (Reel R1774)
    Enable law faculty to complete experimental efforts in legal education and research
    $5,000.00; $4,820.00
    de Spoelberch, Guillaume; Frodin, Reuben
  - Padjadjaran University (07450360), 1974 March 20-1974 September 19 (Reel R1190, Reel R5080)
    Support for a seminar on the management of water resources at the institution of ecology in bandung
    $4,000.00; $3,856.65
    de Spoelberch, Guillaume; Hathaway, Dale E.
  - Padjadjaran University (07850152), 1977 December 07-1978 February 06 (Reel R2697, Reel R5048)
    Support for a workshop on ecological training and education in indonesian higher education
    $3,623.00; $3,623.00
    Hanratty, Martin E.; Smith, Theodore M.
  - Padjadjaran University (07950636), 1979 May 16-1982 May 15 (Reel R4051, Reel R5004)
    Assist the faculty in subscribing to international law journals to prepare abstracts of articles relevant to indonesian law
    $700.00; $673.78
  - Padjadjaran University (08250864), 1982 June 18-1982 July 17 (Reel R3471, Reel R5098)
    To enable the institute of ecology to conduct a seminar in jakarta on "contemporary ecolological thinking and concepts"
    $2,199.00; $2,199.00
  - Padjadjaran University (08250865), 1982 July 01-1982 August 31 (Reel R3471, Reel R5098)
    Support the participation of three staff members in the annual course on environmental impact assessment in aberdeen, u.k.
    $9,300.00; $9,138.90
  - Padjadjaran University (08350440), 1983 April 15-1983 October 14 (Reel R4149, Reel R5080)
    Support participation of two staff members of the institute in a workshop on human ecology in khon kaen, thailand
    $2,867.00; $2,867.00
    Poffenberger, Mark
  - Padjadjaran University (08350914), 1983 June 10-1984 July 31 (Reel R4424, Reel R4862)
    Support course on human ecology in indonesia
    $38,572.00; $38,572.00
  - Padjadjaran University (08400853), 1984 September 01-1992 June 30 (Reel R6750, Reel R6756)
    Staff development and research projects focusing on human ecological impact of current government development policies (indonesia)
    $175,000.00; $174,901.38
    Fay, Paul
  - Padjadjaran University (08450564), 1984 May 20-1984 November 19 (Reel R4823)
    Support for two female staff members to attend a short-term course on identification of insects and handling of insect collections
    $4,018.00; $4,016.72
  - Padjadjaran University (08700714), 1987 January 01-1991 December 31 (Reel R6097)
    Support of community epidemiology research and training activities
    Myntti, C. (Cynthia)
  - Padjadjaran University (08750494), 1987 February 15-1987 August 14 (Reel R5346)
    Technical consultation by centers for disease control staff on the risk approach to improving perinatal health services in west java
    $4,000.00; $4,000.00
    Dibley, Michael J.
  - Padjadjaran University (08950888), 1989 April 01-1990 April 01 (Reel R5775, Reel R5801)
    Support for a study to estimate extent of low birthweight and identify associated risk factors in rural indonesia
    $28,500.00; $28,500.00
  - Padjadjaran University (08951092), 1989 February 01-1990 December 31 (Reel R6528, Reel R6708)
    Support for microfilming of indigenous language manuscripts in west java
    $29,045.00; $29,045.00
    Feinstein, Alan; Hicks, Francis
  - Padjadjaran University (09150103), 1990 July 01-1991 July 01 (Reel R6098)
    Support for the university's institute of ecology to implement the initial phase of the indonesia 2020 project (sust. Devlpmt.)
    $49,500.00; $49,208.68
    Seymour, Frances
  - Padjadjaran University (09150405), 1991 January 15-1991 July 15 (Reel R5829)
    Sustainable development seminar and publications (southeast asia)
  - Padjadjaran University (09151072), 1991 March 01-1992 June 01 (Reel R6336)
    Support for anthropological research on pregnancy and birth in rural west java
    $27,531.00; $27,531.00
  - Padjadjaran University (09251081), 1992 July 01-1994 December 31 (Reel R7061, Reel R7412)
    Research on non-timber forest products
    $50,000.00; $48,901.37
  - Padjadjaran University (09401232), 1994 June 01-2001 August 31 (Reel R9005)
    Support for exploration of the changing dynamics of irrigation and agriculture in areas of rapid urbanization and industrialization
    $515,000.00; $515,000.00
    Pradhan, Ujjwal; Campbell, J. Y. (Jeffrey Y.)
  - Padjadjaran University (09401255), 1994 September 01-1998 August 31 (Reel R8307)
    Support for two experimental training projects in reproductive health
    Sciortino, Rosalia M.
  - Paedagogisches Zentrum (06700121), 1967 January 30-1968 January 29 (Reel R1823, Reel R1824)
    International conference on educational testing
    Germany
  - Paine College (05600431), 1956 June 29-1966 June 28 (Reel R0304)
    $67,000.00; $67,000.00
  - Paine College (06700403), 1967 July 19-1968 July 18 (Reel R1858)
    Financial assistance for faculty members who are planning to pursue advanced study during the coming year
    $10,973.00; $10,973.00
    Crossland, Fred E. (Fred Eugene); Scanlon, John J.
  - Paine College (06800065), 1967 December 08-1968 December 07 (Reel R1215)
    Improvement of the college's business practices by retaining the services of peat, marwick & mitchell as consultants
    Bryant, James W.
  - Painted Bride Art Center (09000662), 1990 July 01-1992 June 30 (Reel R6922)
    Alternative arts organizations commissioning program (001)
    $37,000.00; $37,000.00
    United States; Philadelphia (Pa.)
  - Pakistan Council Of Scientific And Industrial Research (07450176), 1973 September 15-1973 November 14; Pakistan Council Of Scientific And Industrial Research (Reel R1512, Reel R4286)
    Partial costs of all pakistan science conference conducted by university of islamabad
    $1,818.00; $1,818.00
    Frodin, Reuben; Miller, Frank J.
  - Pakistan Institute Of Development Economics (07300151), 1973 March 01-1988 August 31 (Reel R3137, Reel R3138, Reel R3139, Reel R5696)
    Research support, foreign study for staff, consultancies and library support
    Pakistan; Developing Country Programs [DCP]
    $518,042.00; $518,042.00
  - Pakistan Institute Of Development Economics (07650164), 1975 December 30-1976 December 29 (Reel R5003)
    Support in country program of training project preparation, appraisal and evaluation
    $45,700.00; $45,700.00
  - Pakistan Institute Of Development Economics (07700075), 1977 January 01-1978 December 31 (Reel R2971, Reel R4284, Reel R4285)
    Conduct of project planning training courses for provincial officials with assistance from the project planning centre
    $146,000.00; $146,000.00
  - Pakistan Institute Of Development Economics (07750081), 1976 November 05-1977 May 04 (Reel R3096, Reel R3811, Reel R3818, Reel R4282)
    Implementation of training program in project preparation, appraisal and evaluation with the united nations asian development
    $33,000.00; $33,000.00
  - Pakistan Institute of Development Economics (08250555), 1982 April 01-1991 January 01 (Reel R5869)
    Visits to pakistan by members of institute's foreign advisory board and int'l editorial board of the pakistan development review
    $30,000.00; $29,053.00
  - Pakistan National Council Of The Arts (07550151), 1974 December 19-1975 December 18 (Reel R1224, Reel R3146)
    Assist the classical music rsch cell in the office of consultants on cultural affairs at lahore in procuring recording equip/books
    $2,841.00; $2,795.90
    Shaw, Robert D'A
  - Pakistan Voluntary Health and Nutrition Association (08000447), 1980 April 01-1981 March 31 (Reel R3139, Reel R3140, Reel R4248)
    Support for the development of health and nutrition programs
    Harkavy, Oscar
    Iraq
  - Palacky University (09501504), 1995 September 01-1997 August 31 (Reel R6001, Reel R7433)
    Support for the establishment of a law school clinic in the czech republic
    $38,500.00; $38,500.00
    Czech Republic
  - Palestine Economic Policy Research Institute (09700748), 1997 March 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R8395)
    Partial support for a forum to ressearch and debate issues of social and economic policy in palestine
    Lapp, Sharry
    West Bank
  - Palestine Economic Policy Research Institute (10151764), 2001 June 01-2002 May 31 (Reel R8905)
    For research on the performance of the Palestinian economy in light of the current conflict and a survey of foreign trade in services
    West Bank; International trade--West Bank; Foreign trade regulation -- West Bank
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (09050604), 1990 February 01-1991 August 01 (Reel R5899, Reel R5979)
    Support for research and workshop program
    Nasr, Salim; Nygaard, David F.
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (09251239), 1992 September 01-1993 December 31 (Reel R6528, Reel R6867)
    Partial support of a series of in-country seminars in international and diplomatic studies for young palestinian graduates
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (09401152), 1994 August 01-1996 July 31 (Reel R6703)
    Intensive training seminars and master-level fellowships for young palestinian graduates in international affairs & security studies
    Middle East and North Africa (Cairo); International Affairs Program [IA]
    Nasr, Salim; Wiseman, Geoffrey
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (09501195), 1995 July 01-1996 June 30 (Reel R6962, Reel R7226)
    Support for training seminars in international affairs and security studies for young palestinian graduates
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (09700127), 1996 October 01-1997 September 30 (Reel R7214, Reel R7535)
    Partial support for an in-country program of intensive training seminars in international studies for young palestinian graduates
    $123,000.00; $123,000.00
    Gaza; West Bank
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (09800235), 1997 November 01-1998 October 31 (Reel R7340, Reel R7533)
    $121,000.00; $121,000.00
    Gaza; West Bank; International relations--Study and teaching (Graduate)--Palestine; International relations specialists--Palestine
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (09851026), 1998 April 01-1999 March 31 (Reel R7866)
    Support for a program of dialogue among muslim, jewish and christian religious leaders in palestine and israel
    $90,600.00; $90,600.00
    Gaza; West Bank; Arab-Israeli conflict -- 1993 -- Peace
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (09951611), 1999 May 01-2001 April 30 (Reel R8527)
    Support for a program of training and dialogue among muslim, christian and jewish scholars to strengthen knowledge & develop understanding of issues related to peace between israelis & palestinians.
    $72,000.00; $72,000.00
    Gaza; West Bank; Arab-Israeli conflict -- 1993 -- Peace; Jewish-Arab relations
  - Palestinian Academic Society for the Study of International Affairs (10250476), 2002 January 01-2003 December 31 (Reel R9153)
    For an on-going set of activities to promote inter-faith dialogue and disseminate values of tolerance and peaceful coexistence with Palestinian society
    Jerusalem; Intergroup relations -- Jerusalem; Jewish-Arab relations
  - Palestinian Agricultural Relief Committees (09850887), 1998 January 01-1999 December 31 (Reel R8747)
    Support for a program of research and training on gender relations in agriculture and rural society
    $49,500.00; $49,500.00
    West Bank; Women farmers--Study and teaching--West Bank--Women in Agriculture--Study and teaching--West Bank
  - Palestinian Agricultural Relief Committees (09950629), 1999 January 01-1999 December 31 (Reel R8631)
    Support for community and organizational development programs
    $54,000.00; $54,000.00
    West Bank; Community development -- West Bank
  - Palestinian Agricultural Relief Committees (10150754), 2000 December 01-2001 November 30 (Reel R8894)
    Support for a program of economic relief for farmers in the West Bank and Gaza
    Gaza; West Bank; Economic development -- Palestine; Development economics -- Palestine; Community development -- Palestine
  - Palestinian Center for Human Rights (09650387), 1995 September 01-1996 March 31 (Reel R6975, Reel R8699)
    Support for the protection and promotion of human rights in gaza
    Megally, Hanny
  - Palestinian Center for Human Rights (10150510), 2000 November 01-2001 October 31 (Reel R8794)
    Support for enhanced capacity to document and report on human rights violations in the context of the current crisis situation
    Azzam, Fatih Samih
    Gaza; Human rights -- Palestine
  - Palestinian Center for Micro-projects Development (PCMD) (10150303), 2000 November 01-2001 October 31 (Reel R8952)
    Support for the provision of legal aid services to Palestinians to guarantee fair procedures in accordance with basic human rights standards
    West Bank; Palestinian Arabs--Services for; Legal aid--Middle East
  - Palestinian Center for Micro-projects Development (PCMD) (10150304), 2000 October 01-2001 September 30 (Reel R8954)
    Support for Developing a regional network of solidarity in favor of Palestinian families in need of relief and economic and social assistance
    West Bank; Peace--Palestine; International cooperation
  - Palestinian Center for Policy Survey Research (West Bank) (10000907), 2000 April 01-2002 March 31 (Reel R8792)
    Support to conduct research, publish policy report, and organize seminars on palestinian public institutions and on security related issues pertaining to final peace settlement with israel
    West Bank; Peace--Research--Middle East; Jewish-Arab relations
  - Palestinian Center for Policy Survey Research (West Bank) (10150745), 2001 January 01-2001 December 31 (Reel R8999)
    Support for convening meetings and producing policy papers as part of Track II activities designed to preserve the peace process between Palestinians and Israelis
    Middle East and North Africa (Cairo); Human Rights
    Kodmani-Darwish, Bassma; Back, Aaron I.
    West Bank; Conflict management -- Middle East; Jewish-Arab relations
  - Palestinian Center for Policy Survey Research (West Bank) (10151555), 2001 June 01-2002 May 31 (Reel R9101)
    For research and a series of workshops to analyze the strategy, structure and methodology of Palestinian-Israeli peace negotiations
  - Palestinian Center for Policy Survey Research (West Bank) (10301509), 2003 September 01-2005 February 28 (Reel R9062)
    For Track II meetings with international participation to inform the parties involved in the peace process, and for an outreach plan to disseminate new data on refugees' preferences
    Middle East
  - Palestinian Center for Policy Survey Research (West Bank) (10350443), 2003 February 01-2004 January 31 (Reel R9099)
    To conduct research, foster broad participation, and generate debates and ideas for overall institutional reform of the Palestinian system of governance
  - Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics (09701948), 1997 August 01-1999 September 30 (Reel R8415)
    Support for analyzing and disseminating the first nationally-representative survey on palestinian reproductive health
    DeJong, Jocelyn L.
  - Palestinian Central Bureau of Statistics (10001246), 2000 April 01-2002 December 31 (Reel R9098)
    Support for capacity building of palestinians in using statistical data for health policy analysis
    El Adawy, Maha
    Gaza; West Bank; Medical policy--Palestine
  - Palestinian Counseling Center (09950592), 1999 January 01-2000 December 31 (Reel R8752)
    Support for the community and organizational development programs of a palestinian counseling center
    West Bank; Children, Palestinian Arab--Services for--Jerusalem
  - Palestinian Counseling Center (10150305), 2000 October 01-2001 March 31 (Reel R8816)
    Support for the provision of crisis intervention training and counseling
    West Bank; Palestinian Arabs--Services for; Children, Palestinian Arab -- Services for; Mental health
  - Palestinian Counseling Center (10251301), 2002 June 01-2002 December 31 (Reel R9035)
    General support for the expanded provision of essential mental health service to West Bank communities in response to the ongoing crisis
    $100,000.00; $99,909.00
  - Palestinian Diaspora and Refugee Center (SHAML) (09551402), 1995 September 01-1996 August 31 (Reel R7780, Reel R8690)
    Support for commissioned research and workshops on the question of palestinian refugees and the displaced
  - Palestinian Diaspora and Refugee Center (Shaml) (10051075), 2000 April 01-2003 October 31 (Reel R9037)
    Support for a comparative research study on the legal status and social and economic conditions of stateless populations in seven arab countries
    Middle East; Refugees--Legal status, laws, etc.--Middle East; Legal assistance to Refugees--Research--Middle East; Refugees--Middle East--Social conditions
  - Palestinian Diaspora and Refugee Center (Shaml) (10250591), 2001 November 01-2003 April 30 (Reel R9027)
    For a feasibility study establishing a network between Palestinian Diaspora communities and their home country
    West Bank; Palestinian Arabs--Services for; Emigration and immigration -- International coOperation
  - Palestinian Family Planning and Protection Association (09951659), 1999 August 01-2003 December 31 (Reel R9179)
    Support for a hot-line counseling service on sexual health in Gaza focusing particularly on reaching women and youth
    Gaza
  - Palestinian Hydrology Group (10351262), 2003 May 01-2004 April 30 (Reel R9104)
    For information and advocacy activities on the effects of a separation wall between Israel and the Palestinian Territories
    Lapp, Sharry; Azzam, Fatih Samih
  - Palestinian Independent Commission for Citizen's Rights (09851209), 1998 May 01-1999 September 30 (Reel R7898, Reel R8371)
    Support for the publication of annual and special reports of a palestinian national human rights institution
    Gaza; West Bank; Human rights advocacy -- Palestine
  - Palestinian Working Women's Society (09851208), 1998 April 01-1999 September 30 (Reel R8323, Reel R8371)
    Support for training women leaders in negotiation and advocacy skills and for an awareness campaign on working women's rights
    Gaza; West Bank; Women, Palestinian Arab--Services for; Women's rights--Information services--Palestine; Women employees--Information services--Palestine
  - Palestinian Working Women's Society (10000509), 2000 January 01-2001 December 31 (Reel R8795)
    Support for training women leaders in advocacy skills and for educational programs on women's labor and human rights
    West Bank; Human rights advocacy -- West Bank; Women's rights--West Bank
  - Palestinian Youth Union (09950803), 1999 January 01-2000 December 31 (Reel R8635)
    Support for two key community institutions operating youth centers in underserved areas of the west bank and gaza strip
    Gaza; West Bank; Community development -- Palestine; Youth--Services for--Palestine
  - Palestinian Youth Union (10150306), 2000 October 01-2000 December 31 (Reel R8635)
    Support for youth volunteer program to assist Palestinian farmers in olive picking during the current state of emergency
    West Bank; Young volunteers in Social service--Middle East; Farmers -- Middle East -- Services for
  - Palmer Memorial Institute, Incorporated (06400260), 1964 April 28-1964 October 27 (Reel R0271)
    Summer program of educational enrichment for students handicapped by educational and cultural deprivation (north carolina)
  - Palmer Memorial Institute, Incorporated (06500183), 1965 April 27-1968 April 26 (Reel R1254)
    Summer programs of educational enrichment for students handicapped by cultural and educational deprivation
    $60,000.00; $48,500.00
  - Pambansang Kilusan Ng Mga Samahang Magsasaka (09250327), 1992 January 01-1995 March 31 (Reel R7029)
    Support for strengthening peoples organizations in agrarian reform areas of the philippines
    Hollnsteiner, Mary Racelis
    Philippines
  - Pambansang Kilusan Ng Mga Samahang Magsasaka (09450226), 1993 October 01-1996 March 31 (Reel R7861)
    Support agrarian reform through accelerating the shift to leasehold status of tenant farmers on private coconut, sugar and abaca plantations
    $50,000.00; $49,705.44
    Siskel, Suzanne E.
  - Pambansang Kilusan Ng Mga Samahang Magsasaka (09450836), 1994 May 01-1996 March 31 (Reel R7047)
    Support to enhance peasant participation in municipal governance
    Hawes, Gary A.
  - Pambansang Kilusan Ng Mga Samahang Magsasaka (09600643), 1996 January 01-1998 December 31 (Reel R8114)
    Support for agrarian reform and for participation of farmers' organizations in local gorvernance
    $164,000.00; $164,000.00
    Hawes, Gary A.; Siskel, Suzanne E.